Stefanos Stefanou

Software Engineer

⇒ +44(0)7706066959⋈ stefannstefanou@gmail.com♦ http://stefanos.isactually.cool

Personal Profile

I am a Software engineer based in Hemsworth, UK. I am enthusiastic about everything I do, I behave well under pressure, and I am passionate about excellence. I can acquire and apply knowledge fast, and I adapt quickly to any situation. I have over three years of commercial functional scala experience in various firms, working in data-intense event-sourced and distributed systems. My hobbies include interest in Mathematics, Physics and Functional programming.

Core Skills

• Typelevel Scala

Akka

• Neo4J

• Fs2

• MongoDB, Elastic, Solr

Docker

Kafka

• PostgresSQL

• AWS

Career Summary

6/2021 - present Software Engineer GB Group Plc

Role outline

As a software engineer at GBG, i am working on the 'Investigate' Product, providing identity identification, location inteligence and fraud prevention on B2B clients around the world

5/2020 - 6/2021 Software Engineer J Sainsburys PLC - Sainsburys Tech

Role outline

Supporting the unified pricing and promotions system of the Sainsburys Group, a event-sourced data-intensive distributed system, Extensive use of Kafka, Akka, Fs2 as well as various Typelevel libraries

2/2019 - 5/2020 Ascosiate Software Engineer TALOS Software LTD

Role outline

As an ascosiate software engineer at TALOS, i worked extensively on the companys biggest product yet, 'Simply-book', mainly around the backend system. Use of Scala play, Typelevel Scala, Akka as well as Cypress/Gatling for testing purposes

10/2018 - 2/2019 Research Assistant University of Reading

Role outline

Developing customized filesystem solutions for High- performance computers using FUSE(ESIWACE Project), extensive use of C, Python, and non relational databases such as MongoDB and ElasticSearch

Education

2018-2022 Bsc Computer Science University of Reading

Role outline

- First Class Honours
- Dissertation: An AI-assisted decision making system for thyroid nodule classification

Dinstictions

2018 AIIA Low Latency Video Streaming Challenge 2018 (1rst)

Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece

Role outline

Developing a customized solution for ICARUS LAB experimental surveillance drones, transfering real-time video and telemetry data with minimal latency, the end-result, alanStreamer was written using C++, C, QT, gstream

2016 International Open Bidding Competition 2016 (Team 2nd)

Organiser: Université Sorbonne Paris Nord, France

Role outline

Functional prototype of a web information system while meeting all requirements set by a project committee, Extensive use of PHP, HTML/CSS, Node.js and MySQL

2015 28th National Information Technology Competition (30th place, Finals)

Organiser: National Technical University of Athens

Role outline

Greece's national algorithmic student competition, finishing at 30th place (final stage), nation-wide, Various problems focused on Dynamic Programming, Minimum Spanning Trees and various number-theory related algorithms

Interesting Projects

2016	DFS (Dummy File System, C and Linux Kernel 4.0.X)
2016	SScheduler (Stefano's Scheduler, simple linux scheduler implementation for kernel 4.X)
2018	'Java for the few'(Book) (Worked on 3 chapters, Book is used on 2 universities (Uniwa, AUEB))